hello my name is green and welcome back
to another episode of hermitcraft today
is a big big Sahara day we've made a bit
of progress as you can see on the
building but we kind of got stuck so we
went and sort of played around with a
few Concepts before coming up with a
final idea so later on in the episode I
plan on finishing most of it it's such a
huge project and requires so much
concrete that I just want to get the
bits done so that the Redstone guys can
then go in and do their thing but for
now I definitely want to try and focus
on getting my new business venture up
and running so let's change in to our
new skin you ready
so let's change in to our new skin
hmm why hello there
yep we're back as Sherlock green and I
reckon we should head over to Baker
Street I thought what we could do since
we're here is head on into the back room
and sort of theorize about some of the
big Mysteries that are going on in the
server so I've I've got my little
connection board going on and who is
poultry man well
we know who poultry matter poultry man
is retired and he's like sipping a drink
out on the beach he's having a great
time the jingler hasn't been seen in a
long time and salmon the salmon that's
what is intriguing me at the moment
they've made multiple appearances red
starting with Ren then me and curb and
Scar have also reported sightings and
nobody knows who is doing it we've got
to assume that this is a person because
it's clearly a player head and you can
see sprinting particles but how are they
doing this how what is the salmon but
there's not a lot that I can do without
the salmon doing more
oh
that is the sound of customers
who is it Ren and Doc yes that's the
sound of money entering my shop
what
the heck
hello hold on hold on uh wasn't quite
ready for customers can you just turn
around for a second just one second okay
thank you thank you yes sir just uh one
second you know just set the mood and
you know
even enter oh
I've been expecting you boys
[Laughter]
[Music]
so yeah so how can I help you guys today
well we have a case I think you have a
case hold on this is really distracting
let me get rid of this
that might be curious enough to Peak
your curiosity okay I'm listening go on
okay uh in short diamonds were gone
diamonds are back still want to find out
who took him and it looks like it's the
jingler did you wanna know who it is you
want to know you want to know who the
jingler is doesn't everybody on the
server want to know who the jingler is
you you've got you've got your diamonds
back
yeah what else do you need like mystery
your mystery has been solved for you the
the missing Stock Exchange diamonds it's
over you've got them back the jingler
the jingler is not the smartest guy I
know that you know Sherlock green is
after a real challenge the dude cannot
even spell you know yeah I mean Django
he wrote jangled on the thing and then
we did it I mean yes he did it's jangled
well and then it's not the jingler wait
a minute it's not the jingler is it what
did they write on a sign well we can
show you I preserved the evidence
um sir if you all right might kindly
follow us okay right all right how do we
get out of here
there's no exit um let's just uh
[Laughter]
so it's this the the chest and
huh
yeah well
I am a hundred percent sure that this is
not the jingler 100 sure
because you might think oh this is just
a typo easy to make right well if you
look at your keyboard the A and the I
are about as far apart as they could
possibly be
hmm you can't I couldn't just type the
wrong thing next to it and also the
jingler's whole thing his whole thing is
hashtag jingled
right hashtag jingled there's no hashtag
there and
he doesn't ever misspell anything he
that's his whole thing his whole calling
card is hashtag jingled he would make
sure that the one or she would make sure
that the sign was done correctly because
it's the only thing so it seems this is
a copycat maybe the jangler is a thing
now but uh this doesn't fit the ammo
either you know why would the jingler
give you back diamonds as if the jingler
stole them in the first place well it
makes no sense we haven't seen the
jingler in months this is not the
jingler but I do want to know who it is
so I'm willing to take the case
excellent all right um
yeah I think it's time for another
investigation we're gonna nail this
jungler jingler whoever it is down and
we're gonna punish him oh you guys sweet
you guys want to come with me
yeah yeah of course can we well you're
gonna have to change your clothes
I just changed my clothes man you're
gonna have to change them again
I guess we have a case then we do have a
case we do have a case but there's
nothing and I literally mean nothing to
go on from this there's there's zero
clues or evidence that a sign saying
jangled can give me I'm afraid we've got
a bit of a waiting game now to see if
the jangler is gonna do anything else
they may not do anything else it may
have even been it may be a mistake but I
really think this is a copycat and if
they are a copycat we can expect them to
do something else
in the hermitcraft server and then we
can figure out who it is
so a little bit of time has passed since
I met up with Ren and Doc and since then
I've been working on another little bit
of my farm so as you can see here I've
got a very basic pumpkin farm ah is
there a way to stop them falling there
or hopefully I'm not losing too many of
them now why isn't that working uh of
course I forgot to put the Redstone in
typical typical typical typical I think
everyone knows how to make pumpkin farms
but you know this is my first time
making one and I just wanted to fit it
in this tube so it's obviously not the
most productive thing the stem updates
and it pushes the pumpkins off it's very
simple I'm probably the last person to
get their act together and do a proper
pumpkin farm oh I am actually losing
quite a lot of pumpkins the idea is that
down here ow which I've made look a bit
more official with this whole thing this
is like my little mini trading center so
pumpkins reads or sugarcane and then
carrots and potatoes come down here and
then I trade them with Bill and oh you
don't have a name oh comments tell me
what should I name this guy and then I
trade with them and I get loads of
emeralds and I use that to complete
which is now completely done my did you
die box money making scheme all of them
is done and I've even upgraded them
they've got more rockets in they've got
bows and golden carrots like they they
are fully Decked Out
now I just need to go ahead and start
selling them a bit more I'm pretty happy
with all my transport system because the
pumpkins actually just drop straight
down there into water and they all
accumulate the villagers are doing their
thing I've learned so much on
hermitcraft
and I think I'm going to learn even more
when we get going properly on Sahara
because the Redstone that's going to be
done here I think has not really been
done before on this sort of scale I
think this is going to be truly unique
and I think to be fair that they're just
waiting for me to finish building this
which I think we're actually going to
try and do a bit later on but I've just
been busy with all of the Sherlock green
stuff because it's fun to do all the
Mysteries or solve all the mysteries on
the server what are these there's some
cookies here and pressure please do
anything oh yeah there's cookies
everywhere and pressure plates that
dispense cookies
jangled
jangler cookie
well it looks like we've been jangled at
our very place of mystery solving so
well I guess the mystery could sorry
saharia gonna have to wait Sahara you're
gonna have to wait because we've just
been given a bit of a lead I'm not sure
is there some there's got to be a clue
here right there's got to be some sort
of clue that's going to lead me on or is
this just it is of I've just been
jangled
is that it I've just been there's just
cookies everywhere I'm just gonna
message Doc and ren on Discord to see if
they want to come and check this out
with me because it's their mystery and
seeing us there my Doc Watson or Doc
docson and doc renson I think they are
totally entitled and you know what I
want was free food I think they're
entitled to know what's going on yeah I
want this these cookies right I'm gonna
message them and see if they can get
online to take a look at this
um I you know when I said like get some
new threads you really took it above and
beyond
are you really hello anyway the reason
that I messaged you guys is because
we've totally been jangled and I thought
you might want to take a little look
there's loads of cookies like we've been
given free food I don't know if I
haven't actually been inside maybe we
should go inside and see if they've done
anything
that cookie said jangler cookie
so looks like you were right homes
there's absolutely no Jangles going on
in here so it looks like it's just
outside
okay all right all right there's still
no door by the way this is still no door
I'm trying to figure out what's
Happening Here is is this just free food
no I think I think we're looking at a
trail it looks like it continues oh and
follow the cookies okay I'm just gonna
take all of the cookies out of the
droppers as we go because I'm like I
mean let's let's have a little
competition I mean I'm I'm up 29 cookies
at the moment so it's it's quite a
cliche cookie Trail right like follow
the breadcrumbs this tangler guy you
know you can stay around yeah I mean if
he wants if he wants to give me free
cookies
oh I'm down for it does it stop at the
Beacon oh no it keeps going yeah I mean
this this is a lot of cookies
keep going no yeah keep going this is
ridiculous this is really this is really
ridiculous
oh here we are oh here we are here we
are here we are we've got we've got it
we've got it
um cookies for Hermits oh there's so
many oh dude we didn't even need we
didn't even need to good work Hermits
love you all free cookies free cookies
cookies for all the Hermits oh okay so
maybe we should leave we'll leave a few
we'll leave a few leave a few for the
the rest of the server I've got a lot of
cookies you deserve a treat have a
cookie on the jangler is this it is this
all we get is this this is literally all
we get just lots of cookies
I'm gonna just take a few screenshots
but like we should maybe reconvene back
at the the base and shall we return to
Baker Street Baker's job is that why
they've done cookies
is that oh oh that might be why anyway
let's let's head on back shall we
oh hold on hold on no guys wait no hold
on hello yeah I've seen it look up guys
oh oh so that's that's where the cookies
have come from
then what is this I think it's a giant
cookie it's dead giant cookie oh my
goodness this looks delicious
oh wow that actually looks like a really
well baked cookie I would eat that
yeah greetings message hmm message a
message
greetings okay greetings Sherlock Doc
and dog is there something inside a dog
just dog yeah you're just
no
the cookies don't say anything right let
me let me have a little read of this uh
this book here okay
oh there's a book yeah yeah I've got
I've got a book here okay so
all right should I should I do it in
like a uh like a jangler voice
just like what what I imagine Jang the
jangler sounds like yes please all right
so it's like it looks like a little
rhyme
jangle jangle cookies crumble down a
trail it doesn't rhyme at all this
doesn't rhyme it doesn't rhyme all right
right jangle jangle cookies crumble down
a trail pulling my hair out biting my
nails grumbling and growling that's it
um
I thought it was gonna rhyme okay I'll
say it again jangle jangle cookies
crumbled down a trail
pulling my hair out biting my nails
grumbling and growling
um um all right we've got a riddle here
cookie dachshund any thoughts splendid
um
um down a trail
so that's just the jangler let's dissect
this okay jangle jangle cookies crumble
down a trail that's where we've gone to
and we've got here pulling my hair out
biting my nails
okay pulling my hair up biting my nails
grumbling and growling
all right what to deduct all right all
right go ahead hair and nails everyone
uh
oh yes
so what grumbles and growls
who zombies
zombies zombies pulling my hair up
biting my nails grumbling and growling
so I'm get this is this is a clue that's
obviously leading us to the next part of
the the trail I guess
right I can't think of there's not a
there's not a statue or something that's
pulling its hair out or biting its nails
and there's not anything that I know of
that grumbles and growls
in like the shopping district or a
building that does that so I think we
can probably assume that it's pointing
us to a person pulling my hair out
biting my nails grumbling and growling
monsters growl they have nails too I
think I don't know if it I don't know if
the Cookie Monster has anything to do
with it but pulling my hair out biting
my nails is something you do when you're
stressed and grumbling and growling is
something that a monster does so you
might be onto something but oh I'm not
sure I'm not convinced that stress is
behind this at all at all what bro
um yeah that's sure it is sure
it has to be her who else I'm I'm not
convinced I'm not convinced I think I'm
gonna sit on this riddle
well I thought I'd cracked it there
dachshund but um apparently um well
unfortunately dogson you're a Scooby-Doo
I'm gonna think about this a little bit
more I've got lots of other projects
that I need to work on but maybe my
comments can help me out as well but um
okay yeah I'm gonna think about this you
guys have a think as well and I'll uh
I'll let you know if I see any more
jangling going on and likewise if you
see any jangling going on you've got to
let me know affirmative all right bye
docson and Scooby-Doo
wow so I don't know exactly what to do
except it could be stress it could be
leading us to stress it might even be
worth taking a look to see if there's
anything at stress's base looking around
I don't see anything
suspicious or jangler-like and
unless this is the jangler did the
jungler no the jungler wouldn't have
done this that's so cute it doesn't look
like there's been anything done to
stress's base at all
so it looks like the trail runs cold
here whoever the jangler is they also
need to learn how to rhyme
so yeah it doesn't look like anything's
going on at stress's base which is where
I would expect
that riddle to lead if that was correct
so whatever's going on here I think
there's a little bit of a waiting game
needed I have a really good reason why I
don't think that this was stress and
this isn't meant to be an insult to
stress at all I just believe if stress
had made this cookie it wouldn't have
been quite as detailed I think it would
have been more pixel Arty and not quite
as intricately detailed with all of the
slabs and staircases I think there's
only a handful of Hermits on the server
that would do something like this which
leads me to believe that this riddle
might not lead to stress but I don't
want to tell renzen and docson that
right now because I can't be sure I
don't know I'm not entirely sure and I
want to see where this goes first before
we go and accuse anybody of being the
jangler not the chunk has done anything
really terrible they've just given out
some free cookies anyway let's go back
over to Sahara where there's lots of
things to do and one of those things is
actually build Sahara and iskau and
Mumbo have both said that they want to
help me with this so what I need to do
is actually message them and meet up
with those two so that we can have a
little discussion about how to tackle
this and hopefully get a little bit of a
time lapse underway as well all right
I'm gonna go message them and see if we
can meet up I think think Korean
actually has a plan so coming to my
temporary Tsar office that I make we
have our Gertrude the the receptionist
here hello wow jeez yeah don't mind her
she's she's she's she's welcome to
Sahara I
think we're we're not gonna get anything
sold with that type of customer service
oh my goodness anyway do you want some
sand
I've got lots of sand
I don't know if I want to buy sand from
you thank you
okay hope you don't mind this gal I mean
you can sit you can sit on the sofa I'm
gonna sit behind it yeah with a mustache
[Laughter]
how much sand do you have lots it's a
desert
she wasn't like this in the interview
process she was nice all right do you
want to do it outside should we do it
okay
okay that's fantastic Redstone you
haven't got an appointment
okay
oh hi guys you're already here brilliant
oh nice okay this is the worst meeting
room I've ever seen it's a vault it's
not a meeting room it's a vault
ah wait you might want to close the door
because there's a crazy there's a crazy
woman out there what is this redstone
guys okay we need to take a serious rain
check here can we actually run a
business that is the size of Summer
right now we have struggled to get into
the office room you've had a terrible
receptionist yep we can't make it into
our own Vault the vault is totally
butchered I mean that's a good thing
that's a security thing if I remember
that we have this man on the server
agree and he pushes every buttons 500
000 times this world is so safe that not
even we can get into it I think okay
that's a plus so when are you guys gonna
actually help building yeah that's kind
of why we're here yeah I mean I will
realize that we can't just I mean you're
you are the architect like you're an
amazing Builder but but we'll we'll help
you place blogs excellent okay so maybe
we should time lapse this together and
then I can kind of guide everybody on
what the plan is
and then when it comes to doing the
Redstone you can just tell me what to do
and I will go I'm gonna I'm gonna do all
of the placing of the Redstone no no no
no no no no can you hear me still saying
no even though I'm getting further away
no no
and this is the first official time
lapse by The Architects so myself Mumbo
and iskau all built at the same time in
complete Harmony it was a total mess at
one point because there was like this
really big dark spot and about 60 mobs
all spawned in 30 Block radius it was
absolutely insane I did have it on my
time lapse however the footage broke and
it had zero seconds recorded so
fortunately iskal kindly sent me his
time lapse and it kind of feels like a
green time lapse anyway because he also
forgot to press F1 so it got it kind of
feels at home but anyway this what this
time lapse shows is that we can work
really really well together and what
we've made is a super impressive build
it's still not finished it took us over
six or seven hours I can't even remember
how long but we seem to have been
building the entire day but we got a lot
done it looks great and let's take a
look at the final product several hours
later and a full live stream day and
this is what we've created the full
Sahara project now obviously we're not
finished this Project's gonna take
dozens of hours we need to finish this
build here all of the Redstone needs to
go in we need to create a Plaza
however I think you can really get an
idea of what this is going to look like
when it's all finished I think this is a
really fantastic building it's one of
the biggest buildings on the server I
think it's definitely gonna be the
biggest shop
so this is absolutely insane it matches
my base in the background but it's also
slightly different mine's like all curvy
and it's it's very circular with uh and
it's very tall as well whereas this one
is very sort of modern modern Silicon
Valley company style which fits it
perfectly you can see the nice architect
logo and the tree I made during the
stream I'm like really really proud of
this tree it has really nice proportions
need to just make a few more of those
this is going to look absolutely epic
when it's all finished however that's
pretty much all we have time for in
today's episode however there is
something else I would like to do before
we set off
and it involves a comment that I got on
the live stream that I did
and that is the did you die boxes so
what I'm going to do is I'm going to
take one of these did you die boxes and
we're going to put this where it will
definitely sell at some point and that
is on the spawn Island so this is where
you go if you die and your bed has been
obstructed for some reason it happens
fairly infrequently not very often
however it is occasionally going to
happen now I want to utilize this
it looks like someone's already made
some Farms here this is maybe the iron
farm I mean it's because of the spawn
chunks or whatever but what I think we
could do is because of this portal here
we can grab ourselves at least one sail
we don't have to do anything fancy
because ultimately this is not an
official shop
but it might just get one sale
look at that timing look at timing I've
already sold one to scar so anyway I'm
going to put that here and I need a
chest probably
did you die
did you die full gearbox Three diamond
stacks
three stacks of diamond wouldn't fit in
there so Three diamond Stacks that that
should uh be pretty clear and this this
is a captive market right here this
they're not going anywhere well actually
you know they could just leave and not
buy it but if they've gone in lava
imagine they've lost their bed for some
reason and they've died in lava they'll
end up back here before they go in the
portal they'll see this did you die I
mean we could even put like a a little
sign here there we go did you die savior
ahead now I'm only gonna put one box
there because I honestly don't think
we're gonna get many customers going
through here but we definitely want to
catch them while they do this anyway
that is it from me that's the last thing
we want to do that is a fantastic
suggestion that I got from the live
stream yesterday thank you so much and
thank you so much for watching this
episode I've still got my salesman
outfit on from when I sold Ren a box so
we are actually selling these things
they are going to go fairly quickly I
imagine anyway thank you very much for
watching everyone I hope you enjoyed
this video and I shall see you in the
next one goodbye